Finding Aid for James J. Blanchard Papers, 1982-2002
Bentley Historical Library
- Government Relations, 1982-1990
  - Administration, 1982-1990
    - Legislative Correspondence-House of Representatives, 1985-1990
      - Bennett, John (Box 48)
      - Berman, Maxine (Box 48)
      - Brotherton, Wilbur (Box 49)
      - Brown, Mary (Box 49)
      - Browne, William (Box 49)
      - Bryant, William (Box 49)
      - Bullard, Perry (Box 49)
      - Bullard, Willis (Box 49)
      - Ciaramitaro, Nick (Box 49)
      - Clack, Floyd (Box 49)
      - Connors, Jim (Box 49)
      - De Beaussaert, Ken (Box 49)
      - Delange, Walter (Box 49)
      - Demars, Robert (Box 49)
      - Dobroski, Agnes (Box 49)
      - Docherty, James (Box 49)
      - Dodak, Lewis (Box 49)
      - Dunaskiss, Mat (Box 49)
      - Dutko, Dennis (Box 49)
      - Emerson, Bob (Box 49)
      - Emmons, Joanne (Box 49)
      - Farhat, Debbie (Box 49)
      - Fitzgerald, Frank (Box 49)
      - Gagliardi, Pat (Box 49)
      - Geerlings, Edgar (Box 49)
      - Giese, Ed (Box 49)
      - Gire, Sharon (Box 49)
      - Gnodtke, Carl (Box 49)
      - Griffin, Michael (Box 49)
      - Gubow, M. David (Box 49)
      - Harrison, Charlie (Box 49)
      - Hart, Kay (Box 49)
      - Hayes, Michael (Box 49)
      - Hertel, Curtis (Box 49)
      - Hickner, Thomas (Box 49)
      - Hillegonds, Paul (Box 49)
      - Hoekman, Alvin (Box 49)
      - Hoffman, Philip (Box 49)
      - Hollister, David (Box 49)
      - Honigman, David (Box 49)
      - Hood, Morris (Box 49)
      - Hunter, Teola (Box 49)
      - Jacobetti, Dominic (Box 49)
      - Jaye, Dave (Box 49)
      - Johnson, Shirley (Box 49)
      - Jondahl, H. Lynn (Box 49)
      - Jonker, Nate (Box 49)
      - Keith, William (Box 49)
      - Kilpatrick, Carolyn (Box 49)
      - Knight, Marvin (Box 49)
      - Kosteva, James (Box 49)
      - Krause, Victor (Box 49)
      - Law, Gerald (Box 49)
      - Leland, Burton (Box 49)
      - Martin, Bill (Box 50)
      - Mathieu, Thomas (Box 50)
      - Maynard, John (Box 50)
      - Middaugh, James (Box 50)
      - Miller, Judith (Box 50)
      - Munsell, Sharon (Box 50)
      - Murphy, Raymond (Box 50)
      - Muxlow, Keith (Box 50)
      - Niederstadt, Roland (Box 50)
      - Nye, Michael (Box 50)
      - O'Connor, Margaret (Box 50)
      - O'Neill, James (Box 50)
      - Ostling, Ralph (Box 50)
      - Ouwinga, Sidney (Box 50)
      - Owen, Gary (Speaker) (Box 50)
      - Owen, Lynn (Box 50)
      - Oxender, Glenn (Box 50)
      - Palamara, Joseph (Box 50)
      - Porreca, Vincent (Box 50)
      - Power, Thomas (Box 50)
      - Pridnia, John
      - Randall, Gary (Box 50)
      - Rocca, Sal (Box 50)
      - Saunders, Nelson (Box 50)
      - Scott, Thomas (Box 50)
      - Sikkema, Ken (Box 50)
      - Sitz, Rick (Box 50)
      - Sofio, Richard (Box 50)
      - Spaniola, Francis (Box 50)
      - Sparks, Gordon (Box 50)
      - Stabenow, Debbie (Box 50)
      - Stacey, Lad (Box 50)
      - Stallworth, Alma (Box 50)
      - Stopczynski, Stanley (Box 50)
      - Strand, John (Box 50)
      - Terrel, Ethel (Box 50)
      - Trim, Claude (Box 50)
      - Van Regenmorter (Box 50)
      - Van Singel, Donald (Box 50)
      - Walberg, Timothy (Box 51)
      - Wartner, Paul (Box 51)
      - Watkins, Juanita (Box 51)
      - Webb, Wilfred (Box 51)
      - Weeks, Lloyd (Box 51)
      - Young, Joseph, Jr (Box 51)
      - Young, Joseph, Sr (Box 51)
    - Legislative Correspondence-Senate, 1985-1990
      - Arthurhultz, Phil (Box 51)
      - Barcia, James (Box 51)
      - Binsfield, Connie (Box 51)
      - Brwon, Basil (Box 51)
      - Carl, Doug (Box 51)
      - Cherry, John (Box 51)
      - Conroy, Joe (Box 51)
      - Cropsey, Harmon (Box 51)
      - Cruce, Doug (Box 51)
      - Degrow, Dan (Box 51)
      - Dillingham, Fred (Box 51)
      - DiNello, Gilbert (Box 51)
      - Dingell, Chris (Box 51)
      - Ehlers, Vernon (Box 51)
      - Engler, John (Minority Leader) (Box 51)
      - Faust, William (Majority Leader) (Box 51)
      - Faxon, Jack (Box 51)
      - Fessler, Richard (Box 51)
      - Fredericks, Ed (Box 51)
      - Gast, Henry (Box 51)
      - Geake, Robert (Box 51)
      - Hart, George (Box 51)
      - Holmes, David (Box 51)
      - Irwin, Mitch (Box 52)
      - Kelly, John (Box 52)
      - Mack, Joseph (Box 52)
      - Miller, Arthur (Box 52)
      - Nichols, Rudy (Box 52)
      - O'Brien, Michael (Box 52)
      - Pollack, Lana (Box 52)
      - Posthumus, Dick (Box 52)
      - Schwarz, John (Box 52)
      - Sederberg, William (Box 52)
      - Shinkle, Norman (Box 52)
      - Smith, Nick (Box 52)
      - Smith, Virgil (Box 52)
      - Vaughn, Jackie III (Box 52)
      - Welborn, Jack (Box 52)
    - Topical Files, 1983-1990
      - Attorney General's Office (Box 52)
      - Attorney General's Opinions (Box 52)
      - Auditor General (Box 52)
      - Auto Theft Protection (Box 52)
      - Bill Analysis Procedure (Box 52)
      - Bonding Issue, 3 folders (Box 52)
      - Bottle Bill (Box 52)
      - Budget Information (Box 52)
      - Capitol Park Committee (Box 53)
      - Children's Agency, 3 folders (Box 53)
      - Children's Legislation, 2 folders (Box 53)
      - Cities In Schools, Inc (Box 53)
      - Coalition to Improve Management in State and Local Government (Box 53)
      - Cogeneration (Box 53)
      - Commerce, Dept. of (Box 53)
      - Committee on Environmental Quality (Box 53)
      - Compulsory Attendance School Aid (Box 53)
      - Computer Voting (Box 53)
      - Credit Life Disclosure (Box 53)
      - Crime Legislation (Box 53)
      - Criminal Justice System (Ad Hoc Committee) (Box 53)
      - Department Priorities (Box 53)
      - DSO Minority Hiring (Box 53)
      - Detroit Public Schools (Box 53)
      - Floods (Box 53)
      - Flag (Box 53)
      - Eagleton Institute (Box 53)
      - Harden Coalition (Box 53)
      - Harwell, Ernie (Box 53)
      - Health Care Task Force (Box 53)
      - Health Occupation Licensure (Box 53)
      - Heinous Crimes (Box 53)
      - Hiring Freeze (Box 53)
      - Hog Hotels (Box 53)
      - Host Program (Box 53)
      - House of Representatives (Box 53)
      - House Democratic Caucus (Box 53)
      - Housing Issues (Box 53)
      - Insurance (Box 53)
      - Insurance Commissioner (Box 53)
      - Jail Cost-Sharing (Box 53)
      - Legislative Liaison Meetings (Box 53)
      - Local Pre-Emption Gun Control (Box 53)
      - Mackinac Bridge (Box 54)
      - Management and Budget, Department of (Box 54)
      - Medicaid Abortion (Box 54)
      - Medical Waste (Box 54)
      - Military Affairs, Department of (Box 54)
      - Minority Set-Aside (Box 54)
      - Minority and Women Owned Businesses (Box 54)
      - Neighborhood Builders Alliance (Box 54)
      - Partners Against Crime (Box 54)
      - Personal Property Tax-Computer Software (Box 54)
      - Physician's Licensure Issues (Box 54)
      - Property Tax Relief (Box 54)
      - Proposal A-Education (Box 54)
      - Olds Plaza Restoration (Box 54)
      - Oil Companies (Anti-Monopoly) (Box 54)
      - Rural Business Partnership (Box 54)
      - School Finance Reform
        - Plans, 1989 (Box 54)
        - Correspondence (Box 54)
        - Executive Office Meetings (Box 54)
        - Governor's Proposal (Box 54)
        - Legislative Action (Box 55)
        - New Finance Reform (Box 55)
        - Proposals and Summaries (Box 55)
        - Quality Education (Box 55)
        - Miscellaneous (Box 55)
      - Solid Waste Issues (Box 55)
      - Speed Limit Bill (Box 55)
      - State Officers Compensation Commission (Box 55)
      - Tax Fairness Plan (Box 55)
      - Treasury, Department of (Box 56)
      - Veto Messages, 2 folders (Box 56)
      - Waverly Public Schools (Box 56)
      - Wayne County (Box 56)
  - Legislation, 1983-1990
    The legislation subseries is the largest such unit in the Blanchard collection, totally just over forty-three linear feet of enrolled house and senate bills, bill analyses, roll calls, and related materials. These bills are arranged chronologically according to legislative session; within each legislature they are broken out by house of origin (house or senate); finally they are arranged by bill number, which is assigned sequentially within the session and house. This ultimately results in a specific chronological order for each enrolled bill. The bills are often accompanied by supporting documentation, but this varies is degree and type from bill to bill. Unfortunately for the researcher, there exists no readily available subject access to these enrolled bills; one must know the legislature, the house, and the bill number to use this subseries with dispatch.
    - 1983-1984
      - Enrolled House Bills
        - House Bill # 4001-4151 (Box 56)
        - House Bill # 4154-4377 (Box 57)
        - House Bill # 4404-4559 (Box 58)
        - House Bill # 4560-4752 (Box 59)
        - House Bill # 4753-5017 (Box 60)
        - House Bill # 5022-5320 (Box 61)
        - House Bill # 5321-5454 (Box 62)
        - House Bill # 5460-5828 (Box 63)
      - Enrolled Senate Bills
        - Senate Bill # 7-100 (Box 63)
        - Senate Bill # 101-248 (Box 64)
        - Senate Bill # 249-510 (Box 65)
        - Senate Bill # 511-630 (Box 66)
        - Senate Bill # 631-699 (Box 67)
        - Senate Bill # 700-799 (Box 68)
        - Senate Bill # 800-913 (Box 69)
    - 1985-1986
      - Enrolled House Bills
        - House Bill # 4005-4223 (Box 70)
        - House Bill # 4249-4722 (Box 71)
        - House Bill # 4736-5208 (Box 72)
        - House Bill # 5211-5808 (Box 73)
      - Enrolled Senate Bills
        - Senate Bill # 6-137 (Box 74)
        - Senate Bill # 139-425 (Box 75)
        - Senate Bill # 426-875 (Box 76)
    - 1987-1988
      - Enrolled House Bills
        - House Bill # 4002-4197 (Box 77)
        - House Bill # 4202-4499 (Box 78)
        - House Bill # 4500-4740 (Box 79)
        - House Bill # 4741-5101 (Box 80)
        - House Bill # 5104-5448 (Box 81)
        - House Bill # 5450-5966 (Box 82)
      - Enrolled Senate Bills
        - Senate Bill # 2-215 (Box 83)
        - Senate Bill # 216-520 (Box 84)
        - Senate Bill # 526-760 (Box 85)
        - Senate Bill # 762-1042 (Box 86)
      - Joint Resolutions
        - Joint House Resolutions A-P (Box 86)
        - Joint Senate Resolutions A-Q (Box 86)
    - 1989-1990
      - Enrolled House Bills
        - House Bill # 4006-4156 (Box 87)
        - House Bill # 4157-4336 (Box 88)
        - House Bill # 4337-4540 (Box 89)
        - House Bill # 4541-4869 (Box 90)
        - House Bill # 4872-5103 (Box 91)
        - House Bill # 5108-5395 (Box 92)
        - House Bill # 5401-5485 (Box 93)
        - House Bill # 5496-6195 (Box 94)
        - House Bill # 6196-6297 (Box 95)
      - Enrolled Senate Bills
        - Senate Bill # 1-145 (Box 95)
        - Senate Bill # 148-250 (Box 96)
        - Senate Bill # 254-445 (Box 97)
        - Senate Bill # 448-660 (Box 98)
        - Senate Bill # 687-861 (Box 99)
        - Senate Bill # 873-1142 (Box 100)
      - Joint Resolutions
        - House Resolution & House Concurrent Resolution (Box 100)
        - Senate Resolution & Senate Concurrent Resolution (Box 100)
        - House Joint Resolutions A-CC (Box 100)
        - Senate Joint Resolution A-Z (Box 100)
  - Public Acts
    The public acts subseries provides some intellectual access to enrolled bills through its summaries and notes. This access is contingent on knowing the year of passage for the bill. The publication, Acts of the Legislation of the State of Michigan, provides similar access with the advantage of a subject index at the back of the book. The Bentley Library has this publication.
    - Cards/Notes, 1985-1990; 6 bundles (Box 101)
    - Summaries, 1983-1989; 6 folders (Box 101)
- Issues Development, 1982-1990
  The Issues Development, 1982-1990 series consists of a diverse body of materials generated by an office in constant flux caused by the many changing spheres and duties falling to the office. The series comprises thirty-two linear feet of materials, primarily correspondence and memoranda, which develop and define the administration's position on issues, arranged in three subseries: general staff, local government, and special projects. Researchers should note that each of these subseries reflects a distinct function of the office and that the office had varying degrees of control over the work. This is especially true of the local government and special projects subseries, which were included in the Issues series to facilitate access, but which in fact had considerable autonomy. The researcher is advised that the papers of Nancy Austin-Schwartz, head of the Issues Office, are with her other materials in the Chief of Staff/Executive Assistant series.
  - General Staff, 1982-1989
    The general staff subseries is arranged alphabetically by staff member, with parenthetical notes on which issues the staff member handled, and consists of nearly seven linear feet of correspondence and memos. The materials extant from each staff member range from a single folder to nearly two linear feet. This subseries is especially strong in evidencing administration positions on issues related to the arts, education, environment, civil rights, and health and human services. This strength is limited to the years 1983-1986, when responses to issue-oriented correspondence remained in this office; during the second term, responses to issue-oriented mail is retained by the Correspondence Office. These two runs of materials should be treated as complementary halves forming the whole picture of the administration's position on the issues. Researchers should also note that the Washington Office series contains materials related to issues. (See also Correspondence Unit, Boxes 34-46)
    - Susan Arneaud (Human Services), 1986 (Box 102)
    - Patrick Casey (Agriculture), 1987 (Box 102)
    - David Dempsey (Environment, Natural Resources), 1983-1989
      - Correspondence, 1983-1986; 18 folders (Box 102)
      - Topical, 1986-1989
        - Budget (DNR), 1988-1989; 2 folders (Box 102)
        - Environmental Contamination Sites, 1987-1988; 2 folders (Box 103)
        - Groundwater, 1987; 2 folders (Box 103)
        - Ned Lake Land Nomination, 1988 (Box 103)
        - Rebuilding Michigan's Recreation Infrastructure, 1988 (Box 103)
        - Renewable Resources Development, 1987 (Box 103)
        - Toxic Substance Control, 1986-1988 (Box 103)
        - Watching Our Waters, 1986 (Box 103)
        - Water Resources/Treatment, 1988 (Box 103)
        - World Conference on Large Lakes, 1986 (Box 103)
    - Larry Glazer (Health Care), 1982-1984
      - Correspondence, 1983 (Box 103)
      - Health Care Cost Containment, 1983-1984 (Box 103)
      - Retirement, 1982-1983; 2 folders (Box 103)
    - Ellen Globokar (Department Head), 1984-1985
      - Correspondence, 1984; 2 folders (Box 103)
      - National Governors' Association, 1985 (Box 103)
    - Dorothy Gonzalez (Health and Human Services), 1983-1984
      - Correspondence, 1983-1984; 2 folders (Box 103)
      - Topical, 1983-1984
        - Children's Issues, 1983-1984 (Box 103)
        - Food Stamps, 1983-1984 (Box 103)
        - Health, 1983-1984 (Box 104)
        - Infant Mortality, 1983 (Box 104)
        - Mental Health, 1983 (Box 104)
        - Public Health, 1983-1984 (Box 104)
        - Substance Abuse, 1983 (Box 104)
    - Lee Gonzalez (Agriculture), 1984-1986 (Box 104)
    - Greg Morris (Department Head), 1983
      - International Relations, 1983 (Box 104)
      - Public Works, 1983 (Box 104)
    - Robert Morris (Transportation), 1983-1984
      - Correspondence, 1983-1984; 11 folders (Box 104)
    - Mike Murphy (Education, Civil Rights), 1984-1987; 3 folders (Box 105)
    - Nan Reynolds (Education, Trade), 1983-1985
      - Correspondence, 1983-1985; 10 folders (Box 105)
      - Topical, 1983-1985
        - Education, 1983-1984; 4 folders (Box 105)
        - Indian Affairs, 1984 (Box 105)
        - Shiga, 1983-1985; 3 folders (Box 105)
    - Libby Richards (Arts, Tourism), 1983-1986
      - Correspondence, 1983-1986; 8 folders (Box 106)
      - Topical, 1983-1985
        - Arts, 1983-1985; 12 folders (Box 106)
          (including Michigan Council for the Arts)
        - Budget, 1984 (Box 106)
        - China, 1983-1984; 3 folders (Box 106)
        - Disability/Handicapper Issues, 1983-1984; 3 folders (Box 107)
        - Michigan Council for Humanities, 1983 (Box 107)
        - Prenatal Care, 1984 (Box 107)
        - Preservation of Records, 1983-1984 (Box 107)
        - Secretary of State, 1983-1984 (Box 107)
        - Sesquicentennial, 1984 (Box 107)
        - State of the State, 1983-1984 (Box 107)
        - Tourism, 1983-1985; 5 folders (Box 107)
    - J.D. Snyder (Environment), 1985-1987 (Box 107)
    - Shelby Solomon (Director of Policy), 1983-1984
      - Briefing p on Policy Issues, January-March 1983; 1 volume (in expandable folder) (Box 107)
      - Emerging Issues (provided by Legislative Service Bureau), February 1984 (Box 107)
      - "Communicating the Governor's Plan", February 1984 (Box 107)
        (with information on Mental Health Budget, 1983 Tax Effort, and 1980 Ballot Issues)
      - Democratic Governors' Association, 1983-1984; 3 folders (Box 346)
      - Great Lakes Governors, 1983-1984
        - Correspondence, 1983-1984; 2 folders (Box 346)
        - Meetings, 1983-1984; 3 folders (Box 346)
        - Deep Draft Navigation, 1983 (Box 346)
        - Economic Development, 1983; 2 folders (Box 346)
        - Executive Director Search, 1983 (Box 346)
        - Machine Tool Industry, 1983-1984 (Box 346)
        - Minnesota-Wisconsin Dialog, 1983 (Box 346)
        - Regional Biomass Project, 1983 (Box 346)
        - Tourism and Arts, 1983 (Box 346)
      - Midwest Governors' Association, 1983-1984 (Box 108)
      - National Governors' Association, 1983-1984
        - Correspondence, 1983-1984 (Box 108)
        - Meetings, 1983-1984; 3 folders (Box 108)
    - Pat Widmayer (Education), 1983 (Box 108)
  - Local Government (Greg Morris, Connie Shorter, Leslie O'Reilly), 1983-1990
    The local government subseries consists of fifteen linear feet of correspondence from the varying levels (county, city, township, or village) of local government. These materials are arranged alphabetically by locale. This subseries consists of local officials' contact with the state executive and the executive branch response, usually from Connie Shorter or Leslie O'Reilly. Much of this is of a routine nature, but there are some substantive materials. The subseries as a whole provides insight into the process of intergovernmental relations
    - Adrian-Argentine, 15 folders (Box 108)
    - Auburn Hills-Birmingham, 25 folders (Box 109)
    - Bloomfield Hills-Clinton, 29 folders (Box 110)
    - Coldsprings-D, 25 folders (Box 111)
    - East Detroit-F, 28 folders (Box 112)
    - Galien-Hazel Park, 26 folders (Box 113)
    - Highland Park-I, 26 folders (Box 114)
    - Jackson-London, 25 folders (Box 115)
    - Luce County-Mason county, 26 folders (Box 116)
    - Mecosta County-M, 26 folders (Box 117)
    - Newaygo County-Oak Park, 18 folders (Box 118)
    - Oak Park-Q, 25 folders (Box 119)
    - Rapid River-Sault Ste. Marie, 27 folders (Box 120)
    - Schoolcraft-Trenton, 26 folders (Box 121)
    - Troy-Wayne County, 23 folders (Box 122)
    - West Bloomfield-Z, 15 folders (Box 123)
  - Special Projects, 1983-1990
    The special projects subseries is an artificial grouping created during the course of processing and consists of nearly eleven linear feet of materials related to three projects: Cabinet Council on Human Investment, Citizens' Protection Advisor, and the Public Investment Task Force. These projects fell under the domain of Gary Bachula, Candace Avery, and Robert Mitchell respectively. The materials from the Cabinet Council on Human Investment document one of Blanchard's efforts to improve the human capital of Michigan. Avery's Citizens' Protection Advisor papers are arranged alphabetically by department or topic. They reveal an intriguing attempt to bring all manner of issues (ranging from crime and drugs to environmental protection) pertaining to individual citizens under the aegis of one state office. Of special note here is Avery's work on the state of the state speeches for Blanchard's second term. Mitchell's materials from the Public Investment Task Force are arranged by type and document one of the central efforts of Blanchard's first term, the attempt to rebuild Michigan's infrastructure. These materials offer an extremely rich source on this much-discussed phenomenon. The committees files provide a rough subject access to the areas of concern; the correspondence and meetings files reveal the process; and the public hearings reflect the "road-show" efforts to solicit public support for the task force.
    - Cabinet Council for Human Investment (Gary Bachula), 1986-1989
      - Adult Education, 1988; 2 folders (Box 123)
      - Budget, 1988 (Box 123)
      - Dropouts, 1987-1988 (Box 123)
      - Education, 1987-1989; 5 folders (Box 123)
      - Employability Skills Task Force, 1987-1989; 2 folders (Box 123)
      - Human Investment Fund, 1988 (Box 123)
      - Human Investment Task Force, 1986-1988; 2 folders (Box 123)
      - Job Training, 1987-1988 (Box 124)
      - Literacy Action Team, 1987-1988 (Box 124)
      - Literacy Task Force, 1986-1988; 3 folders (Box 124)
      - Meetings, 1987-1988; 3 folders (Box 124)
      - Michigan Opportunity Card, 1987-1988; 2 folders (Box 124)
      - Speeches and Notes, 1987-1988 (Box 124)
    - Citizens Protection Advisor (Candy Avery), 1986-1990
      - A.J. Obie Fraud, 1986 (Box 124)
      - Association of Civilian Technicians, 1986 (Box 124)
      - Avery, Candy, Appointment, 1986-1988 (Box 124)
      - Berrien County/Benton Harbor Equity Grant, 1986-1987 (Box 124)
      - Burtha Fisher Home, 1990 (Box 124)
      - Community Corrections (HB 4164), 1988-1989; 2 folders
        - Northwest Michigan Grant, 1990 (Box 124)
      - Corrections, 1985-1990
        - Annual Reports, 1989 (Box 124)
        - Boot Camp (Detroit), 1990 (Box 124)
        - Budget, 1989-1990; 2 folders (Box 125)
        - Community Residential Program, 1989 (Box 125)
        - Corktown, 1990 (Box 125)
        - Corrections Commission, 1985-1989 (Box 125)
        - Detroit Prison Site, 1985-1987 (Box 125)
        - Health Issues, 1990 (Box 125)
        - Inmate Correspondence, 1988-1990 (Box 125)
        - Psychiatric Facilities, 1989-1990 (Box 125)
        - Substance Abuse, 1989-1990 (Box 125)
        - Miscellaneous, 1988-1990 (Box 125)
      - Crime, 1987-1990
        - General, 1987-1989 (Box 125)
        - Heinous, 1987-1989 (Box 125)
        - Package, 1988 (Box 125)
        - Statistics/Information, 1988-1990; 2 folders (Box 125)
        - Victims, 1988-1990 (Box 125)
      - Detroit, 1987-1990 (Box 125)
      - Disasters, 1987-1990
        - Agricultural, 1988-1990 (Box 125)
        - Fires, 1989-1990 (Box 125)
        - Nuclear Power Accident, 1989 (Box 125)
      - Drugs, 1986-1989
        - Anti-Drug Abuse Act, 1989 (Box 126)
        - Drug Abuse Crisis Panel, 1988-1989; 2 folders (Box 126)
        - Drug-Free Schools, 1988-1990; 2 folders (Box 126)
        - Drug-Free Work, 1988-1990; 3 folders (Box 126)
        - Drug Sentencing, 1989 (Box 126)
        - Federal Money, 1986-1989; 2 folders (Box 126)
        - Governor's Initiative Against Drugs, 1986-1989; 2 folders (Box 126)
        - Straits Area Narcotics Enforcement, 1986 (Box 126)
      - Emergency Management, 1988-1990
        - General, 1988-1990; 2 folders (Box 126)
        - Energy/Gas, 1989-1990 (Box 126)
        - Fermi Plant Drill, 1990 (Box 126)
        - Transbord III, 1989 (Box 126)
      - Environmental Protection Agency, 1986-1987 (Box 126)